Robert C. Hendrickson Papers
Robert C. Hendrickson Papers
- Communications and writings
  - Correspondence
    - United States
      - Department of the Army, 1950-1955 (Box 52)
      - Department of Commerce, 1948-1953 (Box 52)
      - Department of Defense, 1943-1954 (Box 52)
      - Department of the Interior, 1939-1954 (Box 52)
      - Department of Justice, 1949-1958 (Box 52)
      - Department of Navy, 1948-1955 (Box 52)
      - Department of State, 1949-1956 (Box 52)
      - Department of the Treasury, 1952-1955 (Box 52)
      - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1951-1959 (Box 52)
      - Military Academy, 1953-1959 (Box 52)
    - U.S. Army Ambulance Service Association, 1946-1963 (Box 52)
    - U.S. Steel Corporation, 1953 (Box 52)
    - United World Federalists of New Jersey Inc., 1947-1959 (Box 52)
    - Vai-Vez, 1937-1964 (Box 52)
    - Via-Vuk, 1942-1954 (Box 52)
    - Valenti, Jack, 1964 (Box 52)
    - VanAlstyne, David Jr., 1947-1957 (Box 52)
    - VanBuskirk, W. D., 1947-1948 (Box 52)
    - Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1940-1954 (Box 53)
    - VanGelder, John H., 1942-1956 (Box 53)
    - VanIngen B. J. & Co. Inc., 1942-1948 (Box 53)
    - VanWinkle, Winant, 1938-1942 (Box 53)
    - Veterans Administration, 1947-1958 (Box 53)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars, 1946-1954 (Box 53)
    - Vreeland, Albert L., 1950-1957 (Box 53)
    - WRC-Wal, 1942-1961 (Box 53)
    - Wal-War, 1937-1955 (Box 53)
    - War-Wea, 1942-1957 (Box 53)
    - Wea-Wel, 1942-1959 (Box 53)
    - Wel-Whi, 1942-1963 (Box 54)
    - Whi-Wil, 1942-1964 (Box 54)
    - Wil-Win, 1942-1962 (Box 54)
    - Wis-Wom, 1938-1964 (Box 54)
    - Won-Woo, 1938-1963 (Box 54)
    - Woo-Wos, 1939-1964 (Box 54)
    - Wre-Wyn, 1937-1963 (Box 54)
    - Waesche, Donald M., 1942-1949 (Box 54)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1944-1948 (Box 55)
    - Warburton, Herbert B., 1953 (Box 55)
    - Warren, Earl, 1948-1962 (Box 55)
    - Waterbury, C. E., 1943-1951 (Box 55)
    - Watkins, Arthur V., 1950-1954 (Box 55)
    - Watson, Marie J., 1946-1954 (Box 55)
    - Watson, R. E. and A. D., 1938-1953 (Box 55)
    - Weber, John K., 1946-1963 (Box 55)
    - Webster, Warren, 1948-1956 (Box 55)
    - Wedemeyer, A. C., 1952 (Box 55)
    - Wellbrock, George W., 1942-1964 (Box 55)
    - Wellford, John and Marion, 1942-1962 (Box 55)
    - Wherry, Kenneth S., 1948-1951 (Box 55)
    - Whipple, Henry W., 1948-1959 (Box 55)
    - Whyte, James C., 1948-1952 (Box 55)
    - Wick, John B., 1942-1956 (Box 55)
    - Widnall, William B., 1946-1961 (Box 55)
    - Wilentz, David T., 1941-1943 (Box 55)
    - Wiley, Alexander, 1949-1955 (Box 55)
    - Wilkie, Wendell L., 1943 (Box 55)
    - Williams, John J., 1949-1954 (Box 55)
    - Williams, Paul P., 1939-1961 (Box 55)
    - Williamson, Edgar, 1942-1954 (Box 55)
    - Wilmer, Richard H., 1948-1964 (Box 55)
    - Wilmer, Gordon, 1950-1961 (Box 55)
    - Wilson, Gill Rob, 1942-1950 (Box 55)
    - Wilson, Charles E., 1954-1955 (Box 55)
    - Wise, Irvin C., 1953-1954 (Box 56)
    - Wolverton, Charles A., 1936-1958 (Box 56)
    - Women's State Republican Club of New Jersey Inc., 1948-1954 (Box 56)
    - Woodbury Daily Times, 1948-1964 (Box 56)
    - Woodbury Trust Company, 1942-1959 (Box 56)
    - Woolman, J. Reuben, 1952-1953 (Box 56)
    - Works Progress Administration, 1931-1938 (Box 56)
    - Yac-You, 1942-1958 (Box 56)
    - Yale, Wosley, 1949-1954 (Box 56)
    - Yeiter F. Sherman, 1942-1956 (Box 56)
    - Young Men's Christian Association, 1941-1958 (Box 56)
    - Young Republicans of New Jersey, 1943-1954 (Box 56)
    - Zab-Zys, 1937-1953 (Box 56)
    - Zachariasiewicz, Wladyslaw, 1948-1954 (Box 56)
    - Zink, Homer C., 1938-1950 (Box 56)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 56)
    - Cross reference sheets, 1953-1956 (Box 57)
    - Form letters
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1958 (Box 57)
      - On the Bricker Amendment, 1954 (Box 57)
      - On Senator Joseph R. McCarthy, 1954 (Box 57)
    - Index of correspondents, 3x5-inch card files, 1938-1964 (Package 1)
  - Press Releases
    - 1938-1940 (Box 58)
    - 1940 (Box 58)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 58)
    - 1943-1949, 4 folders (Box 58)
    - 1950-1964, 5 folders (Box 59)
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1929-1930 (Box 59)
      - 1940-1950, 5 folders (Box 60)
      - 1950-1953, 4 folders (Box 61)
      - 1953-1964, 4 folders (Box 62)
    - Phonodiscs
      - Hendrickson, Robert C.
        - Interview (Box 62)
        - Presentation of Placard by New Jersey to the U.S. Naval Academy in Commemoration of the Battleship New Jersey, 1953 (Package 2)
      - Hendrickson, Robert C. and H. Alexander Smith
        - Interview, circa 1952 (Package 3)
    - Speeches, Statements and Insertions in the Congressional Record, 1949-1954
      - Miscellaneous (Box 62)
      - Scrapbooks (vol. 1), 1949 Jan-Oct (Package 4)
      - Scrapbooks (vol. 2), 1950 Jan-1951 Jan (Package 5)
      - Scrapbooks (vol. 3), 1951 Jan-Oct (Package 6)
      - Scrapbooks (vol. 4), 1950-1954 (Package 7)
  - Writings
    - Articles and essays, 1939-1955
      - "British-American Responsibilities in the Pacific," Pacific Neighbors, X, 1955; draft and pr. mat. (Box 63)
      - "The Legislator's Viewpoint," New Jersey Municipalities, XVI, 1939 (Box 63)
      - "The New Treason: Corruption in Government," Newark Star-Ledger, undated (Box 63)
      - "Soil and Erosion," Avalon Yacht Club Magazine, 1951 (Box 63)
      - "State Resources Reserve Fund a Bulwark," The Republican Bulletin, 1943 (Box 63)
      - Untitled
        - in The Republican Bulletin, 1948 (Box 63)
        - in The Shield, 1950 (Box 63)
    - Books, nonfiction
      - Youth in Danger, 1955; chapters II-XVI (Box 63)
- Organization records
  - General, 1962-1964
    - Private agencies
      - Christ Episcopal Church of Woodbury, N.J. (Box 63)
      - National Committee for Support of the Public Schools (Box 63)
      - Suburban Homes Building and Loan Assn, 1923-1932 (Box 63)
    - Public agencies
      - Municipal Credit Survey of Atlantic City, 1942 (Box 63)
      - Woodbury Public Library, 1961 (Box 63)
  - New Jersey
    - Miscellaneous, 1941-1949 (Box 63)
    - Board of Public Utilities, 1939-1946 (Box 63)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1946-1947 (Box 64)
    - Child Labor Policies and Regulations, 1942 (Box 64)
    - Commission on Interstate Cooperation, 1941-1948 (Box 64)
    - Commission on State Administrative Reorganization, 1948 (Box 64)
    - Commission on Tax Law Revision, 1937-1940 (Box 64)
    - Constitutional Conventions
      - Miscellaneous (Box 64)
      - 1935-1946, 2 folders (Box 64)
      - 1947-1958, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Council of State Governments, 1940-1947 (Box 65)
    - Delaware River Port Authority, 1953 (Box 65)
    - Executive Department, 1938-1952 (Box 65)
    - Financial Assistance Commission, 1937-1939 (Box 65)
    - Gloucester County Tunnel Authority, 1946-1947 (Box 65)
    - Highway Department, 1939-1958 (Box 66)
    - Interstate Commission on the Delaware River Basin
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1952 (Box 66)
      - Meetings, 1941-1949 (Box 66)
      - Reports, 1947-1953 (Box 66)
      - Statements and Press Releases, 1947-1952 (Box 66)
    - Island Beach National Monument Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 66)
    - Legislature
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1945 (Box 66)
      - Acts, bills and resolutions, 1938; 1941-1942; 2 folders (Box 66)
      - Bonus Commission, 1946-1947 (Box 67)
      - Senate Conferences, 1938-1939 (Box 67)
      - Senate Investigating Committee, 1942 (Box 67)
      - State Pensions, 1938 (Box 67)
    - Monmouth Beach
      - Municipal Credit Survey, 1943 (Box 67)
    - Republican Party
      - Miscellaneous, 1936-1953 (Box 67)
      - "Case for Senator", 1954 (Box 67)
      - "Driscoll for Governor", 1949 (Box 67)
      - "Eisenhower for President", 1952 (Box 67)
      - "Hendrickson for Governor", 1940
        - Miscellaneous (Box 67)
        - Itineraries (Box 68)
      - "Hendrickson for Senator", 1948
        - Miscellaneous (Box 68)
        - Itineraries (Box 68)
      - Scrapbooks (vols. 5-6), 1948; 2 volumes (Package 8)
    - South Jersey Port Commission, 1935-1946 (Box 68)
    - Treasury Department
      - Miscellaneous, 1937-1948 (Box 68)
      - Appropriations, 1938-1948 (Box 68)
      - Memoranda, 1947-1948 (Box 68)
      - Pari-Mutuel Racing, 1937-1946 (Box 68)
      - Railway Taxation, 1941-1942 (Box 69)
      - Unemployment Compensation Commission, 1947 (Box 69)
  - U.S. Army
    - Consultant Duty, Germany, 1947 (Box 69)
    - Military Government
      - Miscellaneous, 1943-1951 (Box 69)
      - Executive Orders, 1945 (Box 69)
      - Reports, 1945 (Box 69)
  - U.S. Senate
    - Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 70)
    - Acts, Bills and Resolutions
      - 1949-1953, 5 folders (Box 70)
      - 1953-1954, 2 folders (Box 71)
    - On the Atlantic Union Committee, 1949 (Box 71)
    - Bills introduced, index, 1949-1954 (Box 71)
    - Calendar of Business, 1953-1954 (Box 72)
    - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1954
      - Miscellaneous (Box 72)
      - Meetings (Box 72)
      - Reports, 3 folders (Box 72)
      - Reports (Box 73)
    - Committees
      - Armed Services
        - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 73)
        - Subcommittee on Public Works, 1953 (Box 73)
      - Government Operations, 1949-1954 (Box 73)
      - Judiciary
        - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 74)
        - Bricker Amendment, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
        - Subcommittee on Civil Rights, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
        - Subcommittee on Immigration and Naturalization, 1953 (Box 74)
        - Subcommittee on Internal Security
          - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 74)
          - Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 74)
        - Subcommittee on Juvenile Delinquency
          - Miscellaneous, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
          - Executive Sessions, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
          - Finances, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
          - Memoranda, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
          - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 74)
          - Testimony, 1953-1954 (Box 75)
          - Transcripts of hearings
            - 1953 Nov-Dec, 4 folders (Box 75)
            - 1953 Dec-1954 Jan, 6 folders (Box 76)
            - 1954 Jan-Sep, 7 folders (Box 77)
            - 1954 Sep (Box 78)
        - Subcommittee on Refugees and Escapees, 1951-1952 (Box 78)
        - Subcommittee on Trading With the Enemy Act, 1953
          - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
          - Final Report (Box 78)
      - Rules and Administration
        - Subcommittee on Privileges and Elections
          - Miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 78)
          - Report of Preliminary Investigation of Senator Joseph R. McCarthy, 1952 (Box 78)
          - Transcripts of Hearings
            - 1951 Apr-1952 May (Box 78)
            - 1952 Jul (Box 79)
      - Small Business, 1951-1954
        - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 79)
        - Reports, 1953
          - Annual, 1952; 1953; 2 folders (Box 79)
          - On Military Procurement, 1954 (Box 79)
          - On Tax Problems, 1953 (Box 79)
          - Transcript of Hearings, 1951 (Box 80)
    - Compendium on the Recall of Gen. Douglas MacArthur, 1951 (Box 80)
    - Memoranda
      - Hendrickson staff, 1951-1954; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Library of Congress: Legislative Reference Service, 1949-1954 (Box 80)
      - On wire tapping, 1951 (Box 80)
    - Military Academies: Appointments, 1954 (Box 80)
    - On presidential recall, 1951 (Box 80)
    - Republican Policy Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 80)
    - Strasbourg Conference Between Delegations of the U.S. Congress and Council of Europe, 1951 (Box 80)
    - Tributes to Hendrickson, 1954 (Box 80)
  - U.S. Department of State
    - Miscellaneous, 1944 (Box 81)
    - American Embassy, Wellington, New Zealand
      - Miscellaneous, 1955-1956 (Box 81)
      - Baguio Conference, 1955 (Box 81)
      - Memoranda, 1955-1956 (Box 81)
      - Social Functions, 1955-1956 (Box 81)
      - Tokyo Conference, 1956 (Box 81)
- Legal records
  - Municipal records, Closed until 1990; destroyed in their entirety, 1991, to protect attorney/client privacy (Box 82-108)
  - Client files, Closed until 1990; destroyed in their entirety, 1991, to protect attorney/client privacy (Box 109-277)
- Memorabilia
  - Bonsal, Thomas F., 1943-1944; biographical material (Box 278)
  - Hendrickson, Olga Bonsal, 1955 (Box 278)
  - Hendrickson, Robert C.
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-1964 (Box 278)
    - Address lists, 1938-1956 (Box 278)
    - Appointment books
      - Personal
        - 1943-1951 (Vols. 7-10), 4 volumes (Box 278)
        - 1953-1956 (Vols. 11-14), 4 volumes (Box 278)
        - 1957-1960 (Vols. 15-19), 4 volumes (Box 278)
        - 1961-1962 (Vols. 20 and 21), 2 volumes (Box 279)
      - Office
        - 1948-1949 (Vols. 22 and 23), 2 volumes (Box 279)
        - 1950-1951 (Vol. 24), 2 volumes (Box 279)
        - 1955-1964 (Vols. 25 and 26), 2 volumes (Box 279)
    - Awards and citations, 1945-1964 (Box 280)
    - Biographical material, 1919-1956 (Box 280)
    - Financial papers, 1936-1956 (Box 280)
    - Itineraries, 1938-1960 (Box 280)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - 1940-1944 (Box 280)
      - 1945-1964, 3 folders (Box 281)
    - Photographs, 1948-1956 (Box 281)
    - Scrapbooks, newspaper clippings
      - 1943-1947 (vol. 27) (Package 9)
      - 1949-1952 (vol. 28) (Package 10)
      - 1952-1953 (vol. 29) (Package 11)
      - 1953-1954 (vol. 30) (Package 12)
    - Visitors' register (Vol. 31), 1949-1953 (Box 281)